tech21.com 2015-03-30

# Tech21 - Privacy Policy | Intelligent Impact Protection

**PRIVACY TERMS**

Tech 21 UK Limited, a company incorporated and registered in England and Wales with company number: 5630013 (who we refer to as "we", "us" and "our" below), take your privacy very seriously. This Privacy Statement explains what personal information we collect, how and when it is collected, what we use it for and how we will use it in the future and details of the circumstances in which we may disclose it to third parties. If you have any questions about the way in which your information is being collected or used which are not answered by this Privacy Statement and/or any complaints please [contact us](https://www.tech21.com/contact-us/).

By visiting and using www.tech21.com (the "Website") or any other application or website ("Application") for the purchase or sampling of products from Tech21 (as applicable) you are consenting to the practices in relation to use and disclosure of your personal information described in this Privacy Statement and [Terms and Conditions](https://www.tech21.com/terms/). If you are under the age of 16, please obtain your parent's or guardian's consent before providing us with any personal information.

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW WILL WE USE IT?**

When you register for an account with us, place an order with us or send us an enquiry, we will collect certain personal information from you, for example, your name, postal address, phone numbers, e-mail addresses and credit card numbers. We may also obtain information about you as a result of authentication or identity checks. We use this information to identify you as a customer, to process your order, to deliver products, to process payments, to update our records, to enable your use of interactive features of our service and to generally manage your account with us and to provide you with information by post, e-mail, mobile messaging, telephone communications and/or through any other electronic means including social network platforms about our products, events and promotions. We may also use this information to tailor how our website appears to you and to tailor the contents of our communications with you, so as to make the website and those communications more relevant to you.

We may also at times ask you for other information, product types and category preferences, age and any special dates (such as birthday and anniversary) which will be used to enhance our service to you. Providing us with this sort of information is entirely voluntary, however we may not be able to process your order if you do not provide us with all the requested information.

We may collect statistical information about site traffic, sales and other usage related information which we may pass on to selected third parties. These statistics do not include any information which can identify you personally.

We may also use your personal information for our internal marketing and demographic studies, together with non-personal data to analyse, profile and monitor customer patterns so we can consistently improve our products and understand what may be of interest to you and other customers.

In addition, for quality control and training purposes, we may monitor or record your communications with us.

We will at all times seek to comply with the requirements of UK Data Protection Act, 1998 (the "Act") and any applicable laws and regulations to ensure that the personal information you give us is kept appropriately secure and processed fairly and lawfully. Your data will be held and managed by Tech21 Limited at Syd’s Quay, Eel Pie Island, Twickenham, Middlesex TW1 3DY, United Kingdom who will act as Data Controller for the purposes of the Act. [Please contact us](https://www.tech21.com/contact-us/) if you have any queries in relation to your data.

**RETENTION AND DELETION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We shall only keep your information as long as you remain an active customer and for three years afterwards or as otherwise required by law.

If you wish to request the deletion of your personal details, or wish to change your preferences at any time please [contact us](https://www.tech21.com/contact-us/).

**HOW DO I UNSUBSCRIBE FROM TECH21 LIMITED EMAIL UPDATES?**

If you have registered to receive updates from us, and you no longer wish to receive these, you can request that we amend your preferences. You can do that either as indicated in the particular communication, e.g. by using the unsubscribe link which is included on all email updates.

**WHAT YOU CAN EXPECT FROM TECH21**

We will at all times seek to comply with the requirements of the Act to ensure that the personal information you give us is kept appropriately secure and processed fairly and lawfully.

**OTHER PEOPLE WHO MIGHT USE YOUR INFORMATION**

In certain circumstances we may share your information with other companies in the Tech21 group of companies and selected service providers who perform functions on our behalf such as fulfilling orders and, processing payments. This includes the companies we have chosen to handle our order despatch service and any delivery company that we may use from time to time. We may also share your information with other companies who assist Tech21 in promoting Tech21 products and services in order to provide you with enhanced customer services and/or share information about Tech21 products with you. In each case, we will only provide these companies with the information which they need to carry out their services and they will not be permitted to use the information for other purposes. They will only be allowed to use your information in the way in which we instruct them and as permitted by the Act.

You also acknowledge and agree that in certain circumstances we may disclose personal information relating to you to third parties, for example, in order to conform to any requirements of law, to comply with any legal process, for the purposes of obtaining legal advice, for the purposes of credit risk reduction, to prevent and detect fraud and/or to protect and defend the rights and property of Tech21 and other members of the Tech21 group. At all times where we disclose your information for the purposes of credit risk reduction and fraud prevention we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that it remains secure.

In the event that we or a part of our business undergo re-organisation or are sold to a third party, you agree that any personal information we hold about you may be transferred to that re-organised entity or third party.

By submitting your personal data on the Website and/or any Applications you agree to this transfer, storing and/or processing outside of the EEA or your country of residence. In the event that we do transfer, store or process your personal data in a country outside the EEA we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that the information is treated securely in accordance with this Privacy Statement and the Act, and other applicable data protection laws.

**UPDATING AND REVIEWING YOUR PERSONAL DETAILS**

You can amend or update your information by logging into My Account on the Website and amending your details as appropriate.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT**

We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. The amended Privacy Statement will be posted on the Website. Please check this page regularly for changes to this Privacy Statement. If you continue to use the Website or if you submit information to us following such changes, you will be deemed to have read and agreed them.

**THIRD PARTY LINKS**

The Website and/or Applications may from time to time contain links to other websites not controlled by us. We do not accept responsibility or liability for the privacy practices, data collected or the content of such other websites. The operators of these linked websites are not under a duty to abide by this Privacy Statement. If there are terms and conditions, other privacy statements or policies appearing on those websites, you should also review them carefully as your use of those sites may be subject to them.

**SECURITY STATEMENT**

Unfortunately transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal data we cannot guarantee the security of your data submitted to us and any transmission is at your own risk.  
We do however use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access wherever possible. Personal information provided to Tech21 via the Website or via any Applications and online credit card transactions are transmitted through a secure PCI compliant server, using,??????? Xxxx SSL encryption technology. When the letters "http" in the URL change to "https," the "s" indicates you are in a secure area employing SSL; also, your browser may give you a pop-up message that you are about to enter a secure area or display a padlock image. Pawel to confirm   
The Website and the Applications use this encryption technology to protect your information during data transport. SSL encrypts ordering information such as your name, address and credit card number. Please note that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered to be a secure means of transmitting credit card information.

**COOKIES AND HOW WE USE THEM**

Cookies are small pieces of information which are issued to your computer when you visit a website and which store and sometimes track information about your use of the website. We use cookies to elevate your user experience and the quality of our site and service. When you enter our site our web server sends a cookie to your computer which allows us to recognise your computer. By associating the identification numbers in the cookies with other customer information when for example you log-in to the site, then we know that the cookie information relates to you.

By proceeding beyond this page you consent to our cookie settings and agree that you understand this Cookies Policy which explains how you can manage your cookie choices and preferences. Please be aware that restricting cookies will impact on your user experience and may prevent you from using part of our website.

**Why do we use cookies?**

So as tllow you to use essential features of our site such as storing your product selections to your shopping basket whilst you continue to shop and/or navigate to different pages of the site and accessing secure areas of the site. If you choose not to accept these cookies, you will be unable to use our site for shopping, only for browsing. To collect information about how you use our site, so that we can improve the quality of our site and service. This information is used by us to:

• provide statistics on how our site is used;  
• see how effective our adverts are by identifying where you click and which website you arrived from;  
• provide feedback to our selected third party partners that one of our visitors also visited their website (including details of any products you bought); and  
• help us improve the site by measuring any errors which occur during your browsing experience.

To provide you with improved site functionality such as remembering if you have visited us before and which preferences you have applied. We can also restore what is in your shopping basket if you wish to return on a subsequent browsing session. These cookies may share information with partners to provide services on our site. The information shared is only to be used to provide the service, product or function and not for any other purpose.

To offer you a customised browsing experience by providing you with interest based services both on this site and on some other websites too. Some of these customised browsing experiences may be linked to services provided by third parties which provide these services for recognising that you have visited our site. This information is used to inform you of Tech21 products which may be of interest to you. These cookies may also link to social networks such as Facebook or provide advertising agencies with information on your visit so that they can present you with adverts for Tech21 products which may be of interest to you.
